The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: So you guys might have heard,
教授：所以你们可能听说过
we have a quiz tomorrow.
明天我们有测验。
So we're going to do a review for that.
因此，我们将对此进行审查。
Did everyone turn in P set six?
每个人都上交P组六吗？
Yes?
是？
Good.
好。
All right, so what's on this quiz?
好吧，那么这个测验是什么？
Numerics and graph stuff.
数字和图形的东西。
So are there any specific pain points?
那么有什么特别的痛点吗？
I have problems prepared.
我有准备的问题。
Now, and then at 8:00 PM is going
现在，然后在晚上8:00
to be a review session for concepts.
进行概念复习。
So now problems, 8:00 PM concepts, tomorrow [? Yakim ?]
所以现在有问题，明天8:00 PM概念[亚基姆（Yakim？）
has office hours at 5:00 PM, conveniently
下班时间为5:00 PM，方便
placed before the quiz.
置于测验之前。
Poor guy.
可怜的家伙。
So take advantage of that.
因此，利用这一点。
So yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: Numerics, on P set we were mostly
观众：数值，在P集上，我们主要是
asked-- you said five, four, whichever came before.
问-您说的是五，四，以先到者为准。
You mostly asked for the running times and things like that.
您通常要求提供运行时间以及类似信息。
But the numeric lecture notes are kind of detailed
但是数字讲义有点详细
and go into Newtonian method and all that.
然后进入牛顿法等等。
How much detail do we need to know?
我们需要知道多少细节？
PROFESSOR: So on the P set we make your life easier
教授：所以在P系列上，我们让您的生活更轻松
by giving you the pseudocode of the code
通过给你代码的伪代码
that you needed to implement.
您需要实现的。
And we ask you one algorithm design question,
我们问您一个算法设计问题，
the problem of finding the k-th root.
找到第k个根的问题。
And that required you to understand
那需要你了解
almost everything that was going on.
几乎所有发生的事情。
We'll want you to understand things that are going on
我们希望您了解正在发生的事情
to come up with something fairly similar to what you've seen.
提出与您所见非常相似的东西。
So yeah, I know that I told you guys
是的，我知道我告诉过你们
before that ignore numerics.
在此之前，请忽略数字。
Just close your eyes and pretend it didn't happen.
只要闭上眼睛，假装没有发生。
Actually it turns out there's a significant amount of numerics
事实证明，有大量的数字
on the quiz.
在测验中。
So we're going to start with a numerics problem,
因此，我们将从数字问题开始，
and go through it.
并经历它。
I'm really sorry about that.
我真的很抱歉。
Clearly I didn't have my way for this, right?
显然我没有办法，对吗？
OK so we started two big things in numerics.
好的，所以我们从数字上开始了两件事。
Karatsuba, which is really easy compared
Karatsuba，这真的很容易比较
to Newton which requires a lot of understanding.
牛顿，这需要很多了解。
So we're going to spend our time on Newton today.
因此，我们今天将花时间在牛顿上。
OK, so anything aside from that?
好吧，除此之外呢？
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: The thing we were just talking about
听众：我们刚才所说的
before you were here was what kind of edges
在你来之前是什么样的优势
are produced by depth first search versus breadth
由深度优先搜索与广度生成
first search?
第一次搜索？
AUDIENCE: And why do they matter?
听众：为什么它们很重要？
PROFESSOR: And why do they matter.
教授：为什么如此重要。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: Because it's probably going to be a question on the--
听众：因为这可能是关于以下方面的问题：
PROFESSOR: So I'm going to go on this very quickly now,
教授：所以我现在要非常快地进行下去，
because I want to cover problems,
因为我想解决问题，
but tonight-- this is on the outline for the review.
但今晚-这是要进行审查的大纲。
So if you guys can make it tonight--
所以如果你们今晚能做到
AUDIENCE: It's late, so I can't make it.
听众：太迟了，所以我做不到。
PROFESSOR: Sorry.
教授：对不起。
Well, they are also in the lecture notes.
好吧，它们也在讲义中。
But I'll go through them very quickly now.
但是，我现在将非常快速地通过它们。
OK, anything else?
好的，还有其他事情吗？
AUDIENCE: Making trees with DFS and BFS,
听众：用DFS和BFS制作树木，
this might be tonight also.
这也可能是今晚。
PROFESSOR: Making trees--
教授：植树-
AUDIENCE: Or your search trees.
听众：或者您的搜索树。
So instead of-- do you know what I mean by that?
所以，而不是-您知道我的意思吗？
PROFESSOR: Do you mean graph transformation?
教授：您的意思是图变换吗？
AUDIENCE: So you've got a tree and you search through it.
听众：因此，您有一棵树，然后在其中搜索。
So then when you're searching through it,
因此，当您搜索它时，
the result of searching it, you can put that
搜索结果，您可以将其
into almost a binary tree.
变成几乎二叉树。
PROFESSOR: OK so how BFS and DFS work
教授：好的，那么BFS和DFS是如何工作的
and how they produce trees, I'm assuming, right?
我假设它们是如何产生树木的，对吗？
Because if you start out with a tree,
因为如果从一棵树开始，
everything's going to be really nice and simple.
一切都会变得非常简单。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: Yes?
教授：是吗？
AUDIENCE: Bidirectional search.
受众：双向搜索。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: Is that going to be included?
听众：这将包括在内吗？
PROFESSOR: At a very conceptual level
教授：从概念上讲
because we didn't give you a P set on it.
因为我们没有给你一个P集。
AUDIENCE: Was that what rubrics was?
听众：那是什么专栏？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: It was bidirectional?
听众：是双向的？
AUDIENCE: Well it's not going to be on it so, we're happy.
听众：嗯，这不会继续，所以我们很高兴。
PROFESSOR: Well I mean we didn't give you--
教授：嗯，我的意思是我们没有给您-
you kind of had to solve a problem just by-- we have
您只能通过以下方式解决问题：
to tell you this is bidirectional
告诉你这是双向的
BFS, go code it up.
BFS，将其编码。
This is bi-directional Dijkstra, go code it up.
这是双向Dijkstra，请对其进行编码。
So we're not going to ask you anything too fancy on them.
因此，我们不会再问您任何对它们的幻想。
So nothing past the P set.
所以没有什么超越P集。
AUDIENCE: Will you have a question
听众：你有问题吗
like when you were studying BFS, saying
就像你在学习BFS时一样
how there will be levels of graphs?
图的水平将如何？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Could there be anything about that?
听众：那有什么事吗？
PROFESSOR: So levels of graphs as in the levels in BFS?
教授：那么图的水平是否与BFS中的水平相同？
Or the levels that we're using when we're building graphs?
还是构建图形时使用的级别？
AUDIENCE: Copies of graphs and then--
受众：图表的副本，然后-
AUDIENCE: Transformations.
听众：转变。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
OK, transformations and layers.
确定，转换和图层。
Yeah, I think this is important.
是的，我认为这很重要。
AUDIENCE: Any particular tips on what kind of transformations
听众：有关如何进行转换的任何特定技巧
we might encounter?
我们可能会遇到？
PROFESSOR: Sure.
教授：当然可以。
Problem one has this transformation, problem two--
问题一发生了这种转变，问题二-
[AUDIENCE LAUGHTER]
[听众笑声]
AUDIENCE: Basically, when do we use these?
听众：基本上，我们什么时候使用这些？
Is it when we are given more than one parameter for a cause.
当给我们一个以上的原因参数时，是这样吗？
PROFESSOR: So I have some problems on this
教授：所以我对此有一些问题
but we have to have a deal.
但我们必须达成协议。
You guys have to help me go through the problems
你们必须帮助我解决问题
fast enough so that we get here.
足够快，以便我们到达这里。
OK?
好？
So if you know the answer, say the answer.
因此，如果您知道答案，请说出答案。
Don't let me wait.
不要让我等待。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: Also, when you run Dijkstra and Bellman-Ford
观众：而且，当您运行Dijkstra和Bellman-Ford时
on a graph, with positive edges, they
在具有正边的图形上，
produce the same shortest path weight
产生相同的最短路径重量
but might have different trees?
但可能有不同的树？
PROFESSOR: Yes, that's conceivable.
教授：是的，这是可以想象的。
Because they--
因为他们 -
AUDIENCE: It's one of the questions on spring 2011.
观众：这是2011年春季的问题之一。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So first off, they both have positive edges, so
首先，它们都具有优势
they both work, right?
他们都工作，对不对？
If you had to choose, which one would you choose?
如果必须选择，您会选择哪一个？
If you had to choose which are going to run,
如果您必须选择要运行的内容，
which one would you run?
你会跑哪一个？
AUDIENCE: Dijkstra.
听众：Dijkstra。
PROFESSOR: OK, why Dijkstra?
教授：好的，为什么是迪克斯特拉？
AUDIENCE: It's faster.
听众：更快。
PROFESSOR: Faster.
教授：更快。
OK so positive edges, Dijkstra is faster.
好吧，积极的一面，Dijkstra更快。
Now if you're going to run both of them,
现在，如果您要同时运行它们，
they relax edges in different orders.
他们以不同的顺序放松边缘。
Right?
对？
So let's say we have this.
所以说我们有这个。
I know you guys remember the sequence of diamonds, right?
我知道你们还记得钻石的顺序，对吧？
My nice example that shows that the number of paths in a graph
我的漂亮示例显示了图中的路径数
is exponential in the number of vertices.
在顶点数上是指数的。
So let's have one diamond.
因此，让我们拥有一颗钻石。
1, 1, 1, 1.
1 1 1
S, A, B, T. So say we're looking for shortest path
S，A，B，T。所以说我们正在寻找最短的路径
from S. Right?
从S.对吗？
So the distance from S to S is zero,
所以从S到S的距离是零，
and everything else starts out as infinity.
其他一切都从无穷开始。
SA is infinity.
SA是无限的。
SB is infinity.
SB是无穷大。
ST is infinity.
ST是无穷大。
Suppose I relax edges in this order.
假设我按此顺序放松边缘。
One, two, three, four.
一二三四。
What am I going to get?
我要得到什么？
If I relax SA, then the distance from S to A
如果我放松SA，那么从S到A的距离
is going to become 1, right?
会变成1，对吗？
Because it's 0 plus 1 1.
因为它是0加1 1。
And then the parent of A is going to be S.
然后，A的父级将是S。
Now say I relax AT.
现在说我放松一下。
The distance from S to T is going to be 2.
从S到T的距离将为2。
Sorry.
抱歉。
Parent of T is going to be A. Right?
T的父母将是A。对吗？
OK now I'm relaxing this one.
好吧，现在我放松一下。
This is going to become one and the parent of B
这将成为B的父母
is going to become S. And as I'm relaxing this one,
即将成为S。当我放松这一步时，
nothing happens because I already had a distance of 2.
没有任何反应，因为我已经有2的距离了。
Now if I relax them in this order instead,
现在，如果我以此顺序放松他们，
so the bottom one first and the top one is afterwards,
所以最底层的是第一个，之后的是第一个，
I'm going to get the different path.
我将走不同的道路。
Right?
对？
OK so what path do I have now from S to T?
好吧，现在我从S到T的路是什么？
AUDIENCE: Right now you have SAT.
听众：现在你有SAT。
PROFESSOR: OK, why SAT?
教授：好的，为什么要参加SAT考试？
How do you compute the path?
您如何计算路径？
Parent pointers, right?
父指针，对不对？
Start at T, look at the parent pointer.
从T开始，查看父指针。
Look at the parent pointer.
查看父指针。
So because I relax them in this order,
因此，因为我以此顺序放松他们，
this path was considered before this path.
该路径先于该路径被考虑。
So the parent pointer of T is A but if I relax them
所以T的父指针是A但如果我放松它们
in the other order, the parent pointer could be B.
按照另一种顺序，父指针可以是B。
So by the way, this could happen if you're
顺便说一句，如果您
running Dijkstra or Bellman-Ford.
运行Dijkstra或Bellman-Ford。
Or if you're running Dijkstra, it's
或者，如果您正在运行Dijkstra，那就是
just about how you're going to have the ties separated.
关于您将如何分离关系。
So your priority queue implementation
因此，您的优先级队列实现
might give you different paths.
可能会给您不同的路径。
Does it make sense now?
现在有意义吗？
So if the order in which edges are relaxed.
因此，如果边缘松弛的顺序。
That's what defines with path you're going to end up with.
这就是您要最终确定的路径的定义。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Hopefully useful.
希望有用。
All right.
好吧。
I saw four hands before.
我以前看过四只手。
AUDIENCE: Oh, just overall, how similar
听众：哦，总体而言，有多相似
is this test compared to previous tests?
该测试与以前的测试相比吗？
PROFESSOR: Less algorithm design, more concepts.
教授：更少的算法设计，更多的概念。
AUDIENCE: Nice.
听众：很好。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Well OK, not less algorithm--
教授：好吧，不少算法-
so it's not going to be as much out-of-the-box thinking,
因此不会有太多的开箱即用的想法，
it's going to be a lot more of what we drilled already.
这将是我们已经钻探的更多内容。
So as a hint, what kind of problem
所以暗示一下，什么样的问题
did we practice over, and over, and over?
我们一遍又一遍地练习吗？
AUDIENCE: States
观众：州
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Graph transformation, right?
图变换，对不对？
So chances are you'll see that.
因此，您很可能会看到这一点。
AUDIENCE: Wait, what's graph transformation?
听众：等等，图变换是什么？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
PROFESSOR: So we start with a complicated problem
教授：所以我们从一个复杂的问题开始
and reduce it to a shortest path problem or to a shortest length
并将其减少到最短路径问题或最短长度
path problem.
路径问题。
OK.
好。
Cool.
凉。
So that being said, let's go.
话虽这么说，走吧。
Numerics, everyone's favorite topic.
数字，每个人最喜欢的话题。
So suppose we're trying to compute this.
因此，假设我们正在尝试对此进行计算。
Cube root of 6,006.
立方根为6,006。
And the problem statement says this,
问题陈述说，
you start out with an initial approximation of one,
您开始时的初始近似值为1，
and it wants two approximations after that.
然后需要两个近似值。
The problem also tells you which function we're going to use.
该问题还告诉您我们将使用哪个功能。
But why don't we make this fun and try
但是，为什么我们不做这个有趣的尝试
to guess what the function will be?
猜猜函数是什么？
AUDIENCE: x cubed minus 6,006?
观众：x减6006？
PROFESSOR: OK. x cubed minus 6,006
教授：好的。 x立方减6,006
why did I choose this function?
为什么选择此功能？
Well, not me.
好吧，不是我。
Why did you choose this function?
为什么选择此功能？
AUDIENCE: It's the root.
听众：这是根源。
PROFESSOR: OK so reason number one-- right?
教授：好的，所以原因一是吧？
Important.
重要。
Has to be zero at the answer, because that's
答案必须为零，因为那是
what Newton's method gives us.
牛顿的方法给我们带来了什么。
And what else?
还有什么？
AUDIENCE: Multiplication is easy.
听众：乘法很容易。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So it's easy to compute whatever Newton's method wants
所以很容易计算牛顿方法想要的
us to compute.
我们来计算。
What does Newton's method want us to compute?
牛顿的方法要我们计算什么？
So given an approximation, xi, how do we
因此，给定一个近似值xi
get to the next approximation, xi plus 1.
得到下一个近似值xi加1。
Formula.
式。
By the way, this formula should be on your cheat sheets.
顺便说一句，这个公式应该在备忘单上。
If it's not, no sympathy for you.
如果不是这样，那么您就不会同情。
AUDIENCE: I don't remember.
听众：我不记得了。
xi plus f over f prime.
xi加f超过f素数。
AUDIENCE: Where's the prime?
听众：最主要的地方在哪里？
AUDIENCE: Prime's on the bottom.
听众：Prime在最下面。
PROFESSOR: So yeah, where's the prime?
教授：是的，总理在​​哪里？
And is this right?
是这样吗？
AUDIENCE: Isn't there a constant?
听众：不是常数吗？
AUDIENCE: Isn't it minus?
听众：不是吗？
PROFESSOR: Isn't it minus?
教授：不是吗？
AUDIENCE: Maybe.
听众：也许吧。
AUDIENCE: There you go.
听众：你去。
PROFESSOR: So yeah, if you guys start out
教授：是的，如果你们开始
with the wrong formula you'd get the wrong answer.
用错误的公式，您将得到错误的答案。
Again, no sympathy.
再次，没有同情。
So get that on your sheets.
所以把它放在你的床单上。
OK so this is what we need to compute, right?
好，这就是我们需要计算的，对吗？
You start with an approximation and you have to subtract this.
您从一个近似值开始，必须减去它。
So this has to be easy to compute.
因此，这必须易于计算。
What if I chose instead a very nice function.
如果我选择了一个非常好的功能该怎么办。
x-- sorry, x minus.
x-抱歉，x减。
This is clearly zero where I want it to be, right?
显然我希望它是零，对吗？
AUDIENCE: But we don't know what six--
听众：但是我们不知道六个-
PROFESSOR: But if I'm trying to compute
教授：但是如果我要计算
the successive approximations, very good, I'm getting what?
逐次逼近法，非常好，我得到了什么？
f of x over f prime of x is x minus square root 3 6,006
x在f的素数上的f是x减去平方根3 6,006
over-- what's the derivative of this?
结束-这是什么派生？
AUDIENCE: One.
听众：一。
PROFESSOR: One.
教授：一个。
So I haven't done anything, right?
所以我什么也没做，对吧？
In order to compute the successive approximation,
为了计算逐次逼近，
I have to know this number.
我必须知道这个号码。
So this doesn't get me anywhere, that's why it's a bad function.
因此，这无助于我，这就是为什么它的功能不好。
By the way, it's not enough that this is easy to compute.
顺便说一句，简单计算是不够的。
What you want is this guy has to be easy to compute.
您想要的是这个家伙必须易于计算。
In the case of division, we had a function
在除法的情况下，我们有一个功能
that looked pretty wacky.
看起来很古怪。
But then when we divided that by the derivative,
但是当我们将其除以导数时，
we got something reasonably nice.
我们得到了相当不错的东西。
So this has to be easy to compute.
因此，这必须易于计算。
AUDIENCE: So we changed it from that one to this one just
听众：所以我们把它从那一个改为了这个
because this one is easier or--
因为这比较容易，或者-
PROFESSOR: So we're using this one
教授：所以我们正在使用这个
because this one-- let's see how easy this one is to compute.
因为这一点-让我们来看看计算这一点有多容易。
Computing this one requires that you know the answer
计算这一项需要您知道答案
to your original problem, which is not cool.
原来的问题，这并不酷。
Right.
对。
So you're trying to compute this number.
因此，您正在尝试计算此数字。
But if you use this, Newton's approximation
但是如果使用这个，牛顿的近似值
requires that you compute this.
要求您对此进行计算。
So you have to know this here.
所以你必须在这里知道这一点。
Which is what you're trying to do in the first place.
首先是您要尝试的。
AUDIENCE: Wait, I'm confused.
听众：等等，我很困惑。
We went from x cubed minus 6 over 6
我们从x立方减6减去6
to x minus cube root of 6 over 6.
减去x减去6的立方根6。
So what's your--
那你是...
PROFESSOR: So this is a good function.
教授：这是一个很好的功能。
We can use this.
我们可以使用它。
This is a bad function and I was asking
这是一个不好的功能，我问
why is this a bad function.
为什么这是一个不好的功能。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So lets see, if we try to compute it using this,
因此，让我们看看，如果我们尝试使用此方法进行计算，
what do we get?
我们得到什么？
xi minus
西减
AUDIENCE: x cubed minus 6,006.
观众：x减6006。
PROFESSOR: X cubed minus 6,006.
教授：X立方减6,006。
Divided by--
除以 -
AUDIENCE: 3x cubed.
观众：3倍立方体。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So someone simplify this for me.
所以有人为我简化了。
AUDIENCE: 6i minus x over 3 plus 6,006 over 3 squared.
观众：6i减去x超过3，再加上6006超过3的平方。
Oh, well.
那好吧。
It's 2,002.
PROFESSOR: I'll choose the easy step.
教授：我将选择简单的步骤。
OK.
好。
So what's x1?
那么x1是什么？
AUDIENCE: You plug in x0.
听众：您插入x0。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
I heard a 2,002.
我听到了2002。
I don't think it's-- it's very close.
我不认为这很接近。
AUDIENCE: 2,002 and two thirds.
听众：2,002和三分之二。
0.67.
0.67。
PROFESSOR: OK, cool.
教授：好的，很酷。
So 0.67, let's get to that later.
所以0.67，让我们稍后再谈。
I don't like fractional numbers.
我不喜欢小数。
I mean this is the right answer math-wise,
我的意思是这是数学上正确的答案，
but we'll get to that because if we want to code this up,
但是我们会解决的，因为如果我们要对此进行编码，
we probably don't want fractional numbers.
我们可能不想要分数。
So very good point there.
那里很好。
What if I want to compute x2?
如果我想计算x2怎么办？
I take this guy and I plug it into where?
我带这个家伙，我把它插入哪里？
This thing over here, right?
这东西在这里，对吗？
So this way I can compute approximations
这样我就可以计算近似值
that get closer and closer to my original value.
越来越接近我的原始价值。
OK.
好。
Does this ring a bell?
这会响吗？
Yes, everyone is happy with this?
是的，每个人对此都很满意？
Cool.
凉。
So how about the initial guess?
那么最初的猜测呢？
Here we started with a known initial guess.
在这里，我们从一个已知的初始猜测开始。
Is this a good guess?
这是一个很好的猜测吗？
AUDIENCE: It's a really bad guess.
听众：这是一个很糟糕的猜测。
2,002?
PROFESSOR: No, I mean 1.
教授：不，我是说1。
AUDIENCE: 1?
听众：1？
That's also a really bad guess.
这也是一个非常糟糕的猜测。
AUDIENCE: Why would you even ask?
听众：你为什么还要问？
AUDIENCE: 11 and a half.
听众：11岁半。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So you're saying 11 and a half would be a nice guess.
所以您说的是11点半是一个不错的猜测。
So, first off, let's see, what do we
所以，首先，让我们看看
need to-- what does Newton's algorithm guarantee?
需要-牛顿算法保证什么？
What-- if the guess is really, really bad,
怎样-如果猜测真的非常糟糕，
would we get an answer all the time?
我们会一直得到答案吗？
Maybe takes forever but we'll get an answer.
也许需要永远，但是我们会得到答案。
True or false?
对或错？
AUDIENCE: True.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Not true.
教授：不对。
Sorry.
抱歉。
AUDIENCE: But it has to be right for your answer to be--
听众：但是您的答案必须正确-
PROFESSOR: OK, so what does Newton's method guarantee?
教授：好的，那么牛顿法能保证什么呢？
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[插入语音]
PROFESSOR: Yep, yep.
教授：是的。
So what is the fancy math name for that?
那么，那花哨的数学名字是什么？
AUDIENCE: Quadratic convergence or something.
听众：二次收敛或类似的东西。
PROFESSOR: Quadratic convergence, all right.
教授：二次收敛，很好。
So this is what Newton guarantees.
这就是牛顿所保证的。
Quadratic-- so what does this mean?
二次方-这是什么意思？
For all your approximations, they're all going to be xi.
对于您的所有近似值，它们都是xi。
If we write them as true answer times 1 plus error, i.
如果我们将它们写为真实答案乘以1加错误，即为i。
So this error is the relative error of the approximation.
因此，该误差是近似值的相对误差。
Newtons method guarantees that the error at each step
牛顿法保证了每一步的误差
is squared.
平方。
So if this guy-- if E0 is greater than 1,
因此，如果这个人-如果E0大于1，
would we get an answer?
我们会得到答案吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: OK so what we need?
教授：好的，我们需要什么？
What's the minimum that we need?
我们需要的最低限度是多少？
E0 has to be between what and what?
E0必须介于什么和什么之间？
AUDIENCE: Negative 1?
观众：负面1？
AUDIENCE: Is it negative 1, 1 or 0 and 1?
观众：是负数1、1还是0和1？
AUDIENCE: It would be 0 and 1, right?
听众：会是0和1，对吧？
Because won't it be less than one?
因为会不会少于一个？
AUDIENCE: Negative 1.
听众：负面1。
AUDIENCE: Oh, absolute value.
听众：哦，绝对值。
PROFESSOR: I think if you score something smaller
教授：我想如果您的分数较小
than negative 1 you get a positive
比负1你得到正
and then-- so, let's say this works.
然后-可以说这可行。
So then x0 has to be between what and what
因此，x0必须介于什么和什么之间
in relation to the real answer?
相对于真正的答案？
AUDIENCE: The real answer minus x0 over [INAUDIBLE].
听众：实际答案是[听不清]时减去x0。
AUDIENCE: 2 times the actual answer is 0.
听众：实际答案的2倍为0。
PROFESSOR: OK so this is a sucky guess.
教授：好的，这是一个令人毛骨悚然的猜测。
We can do a lot better, but at least it
我们可以做得更好，但至少可以做到
will make the thing converge.
会使事情收敛。
Fair enough?
很公平？
OK now what if I want a good guess?
好吧，如果我想猜猜该怎么办？
First off, let's backtrack to a more general problem
首先，让我们回溯到更普遍的问题
because this is easy, right?
因为这很容易，对吗？
To plug it into our calculator and you have the answer.
要将其插入我们的计算器，您将获得答案。
So what if I'm trying to compute cube root of r.
那么，如果我尝试计算r的立方根怎么办。
Can everyone see, by the way?
大家可以顺便看到吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Mhmm.
听众：嗯。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So I'm trying to compute cube root of r.
所以我正在尝试计算r的立方根。
r is a number.
r是一个数字。
Suppose I'm trying to compute, for example, cube root of 2.
假设我尝试计算例如2的立方根。
What's the first thing I need to do?
我需要做的第一件事是什么？
I'm going to code this up, by the way.
顺便说一下，我将对此进行编码。
Well, not me but suppose we want to code this up.
好吧，不是我，而是假设我们要对此进行编码。
What's the first thing we want to do?
我们要做的第一件事是什么？
AUDIENCE: I think we want an initial guess at a function.
听众：我认为我们想对某个功能进行初步猜测。
PROFESSOR: OK so we're going to need an initial guess.
教授：好的，我们需要初步猜测。
That's good.
那很好。
And what else do we want?
我们还想要什么？
AUDIENCE: We need to decide how much precision we want.
听众：我们需要决定想要多少精度。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
And why is that?
为什么是这样？
AUDIENCE: Because this cube root of 2 is 1.
听众：因为这个2的立方根是1。
If you round down.
如果您舍入。
That doesn't tell us very much.
那并不能告诉我们太多。
I don't know, we don't like the fractions.
我不知道，我们不喜欢这些分数。
PROFESSOR: We don't like fractions.
教授：我们不喜欢分数。
OK, why don't we like fractions?
好吧，为什么我们不喜欢分数呢？
It's a lot easier to code.
编写代码要容易得多。
AUDIENCE: Decimal point there.
听众：小数点在那里。
PROFESSOR: Yep, you have to deal with the decimal point
教授：是的，您必须处理小数点
and we don't like that.
而且我们不喜欢这样。
So we want to take this problem, and we
所以我们想解决这个问题，我们
want to move it into integer land.
想要将其移动到整数域。
So what we did here has fractions.
因此，我们在这里所做的事情很少。
We don't like that because that's a pain to code.
我们不喜欢那样，因为那是编写代码的痛苦。
We didn't make you code fractions on the P set, right?
我们没有让您在P集上编码分数，对吗？
So then we better know how to avoid fractions
所以我们更好地知道如何避免分数
if you want to solve real life problems.
如果您想解决现实生活中的问题。
So we're going to say that we're happy with some amount
所以我们要说，我们对一定金额感到满意
of precision in the answer.
精确的答案。
And then we're going to do something
然后我们要做点什么
that lets us do all our computations in integer land.
这样我们就可以在整数域中进行所有计算。
Because that's a happy place.
因为那是一个快乐的地方。
So how do I-- suppose I'm working in base B
那我怎么-假设我在B基地工作
and I want d digits of precision.
我想要d位精度。
What do I want to compute?
我要计算什么？
How do I transform the problem in that way?
如何以这种方式解决问题？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: You multiply 2 root 3 times B to the d.
听众：将2的根乘以B的3倍。
PROFESSOR: OK so we want the answer
教授：好的，我们想要答案
to be 2 times B to the d.
是d的B的2倍。
And if we're integer land, what are we actually going to get?
如果我们是整数土地，我们实际上将得到什么？
So suppose B is 10-- let's work with familiar numbers-- d is 2.
因此，假设B为10-让我们使用熟悉的数字-d为2。
So we're going to want to compute
所以我们要计算
square root of 3 2 times 100.
3 2的平方根乘以100。
Does anyone have a calculator and can tell me
有人有计算器可以告诉我吗
what square root of 3 is?
3的平方根是多少？
First two digits?
前两位数字？
AUDIENCE: Cube root of 2.
听众：2的立方根。
PROFESSOR: Sorry, cube root of 2.
教授：对不起，立方根为2。
AUDIENCE: 1.2.
听众：1.2。
PROFESSOR: So let's say that square root of 3 is 1.2345.
教授：所以我们说3的平方根是1.2345。
Hopefully someone will fix this up for us.
希望有人会为我们解决这个问题。
But let's say it's this.
但是，可以说就是这个。
If I multiply it by 100 what do I get?
如果我乘以100，我会得到什么？
123 times 45.
123倍45。
So multiply by 100 means you move the decimal point
所以乘以100表示​​您移动小数点
to the right.
在右边。
Right?
对？
So it's still not an integer.
所以它仍然不是整数。
If we work in integer land, our algorithm
如果我们在整数土地上工作，我们的算法
will return an integer.
将返回一个整数。
What's the integer that we're hoping
我们希望的整数是多少
our algorithm will return?
我们的算法会返回吗？
AUDIENCE: 1.23, right?
听众：1.23对吧？
PROFESSOR: We're hoping so, right?
教授：我们希望如此，对吗？
Why?
为什么？
What can you do with 123?
123可以做什么？
Shift right.
向右移动。
So if you divide this by 100, you get 1.23.
因此，如果将其除以100，则得到1.23。
And this is our answer with two digits of precision.
这是我们的答案，精度为两位数。
AUDIENCE: Do you want the actual-- it's 1.2599.
听众：您是否想要真实的-1.2599。
PROFESSOR: You guys are good.
教授：你们很好。
OK.
好。
So our algorithm will give us this, right?
所以我们的算法会给我们这个，对吗？
So it's not going to give us exactly cube
所以这不会给我们确切的立方体
root of 2 times 100.
2的根100。
It's not going to give us exactly this value.
它不会给我们确切的价值。
What's it going to give us?
这将给我们带来什么？
AUDIENCE: Two digits-- close to that.
受众：两位数-接近该数字。
PROFESSOR: So it's going to give us an integer, right?
教授：因此，它将给我们一个整数，对吗？
So what kind of integer?
那么什么样的整数呢？
Math.
数学。
AUDIENCE: Truncated?
听众：被截断了吗？
PROFESSOR: OK, what's the math for that?
教授：好的，这是什么数学？
Truncated.
被截断了。
Floor.
地板。
Very good.
很好。
So this is what we're actually going to compute.
这就是我们实际要计算的。
Actually, because we're in integer land,
实际上，因为我们处在整数土地上，
we're going to have floors at every step
我们将在每一步都铺地板
when we're doing that approximation.
当我们这样做的时候。
And there's a fancy proof for Newton
牛顿有花哨的证据
that says that even though you're taking floors
这说明即使您要发言
all the time, it will still converge to the right thing.
一直以来，它仍然会收敛于正确的事物。
So in order to compute this, how are we
所以为了计算这个，我们如何
going to transform the problem?
要改变这个问题？
AUDIENCE: Slide the Bd into that.
听众：将Bd插入其中。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: You're going to have to put a 3 in there.
听众：您将不得不在其中放置3。
B to the 3d.
B到3d。
PROFESSOR: So we're actually going
教授：所以我们实际上要去
to compute cube root of 2 times B to the 3d.
计算3倍B的2倍的立方根。
Fair enough?
很公平？
And if we slide this right by the digits
如果我们按数字向右滑动
afterwards we're going to get our two digits of precision.
之后，我们将获得两位数的精度。
OK.
好。
So now I figured out my precision.
所以现在我想出了我的精度。
I want an initial guess-- and actually I lied,
我想要一个初步的猜测-实际上我撒了谎，
there's one more problem.
还有一个问题。
Running time.
运行时间。
Do you guys want to start with the running time
你们要开始跑步吗
or initial guess?
还是最初的猜测？
AUDIENCE: Initial guess.
听众：初步猜测。
PROFESSOR: OK so what I want a good initial guess?
教授：好的，那么我想作一个初步的猜测吗？
AUDIENCE: Between 0 and 2x.
听众：0到2倍之间。
PROFESSOR: OK so if I don't have that the algorithm will
教授：好的，如果我没有那个算法，
crash and burn.
崩溃和燃烧。
When we did Newton in recitation,
当我们背诵牛顿时
I said that I would like two things.
我说我想两件事。
And I backed up, I coded that into P set five
然后我备份，将其编码为P组5
when I did the guess.
我猜的时候
So what are the two things that I
那我有两件事是什么
want from a good initial guess?
想要从一个好的初始猜测中得出？
AUDIENCE: Order of magnitude?
听众：数量级？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Perfect.
完善。
AUDIENCE: Oh, god.
听众：哦，天哪。
[LAUGHS]
[笑声]
PROFESSOR: OK, so order of magnitude
教授：好的，数量级
is a fancy CSE way to say, right number of digits.
是一种奇妙的CSE说法，正确的数字位数。
Suppose we're computing this.
假设我们正在计算这个。
Or suppose we're computing the cube
或者假设我们正在计算多维数据集
root of some number in base B. So
以B为底数的根
supposed r is somewhere between 0 and B.
假设r在0到B之间。
It's one digit in base B. How many digits
基数为B的一位数字。
is this result is going to have?
这个结果将会有吗？
AUDIENCE: The amount of digits divided by 3.
观众：数字除以3。
The amount of digits in 2 times B to the 3d.
2倍B到3d的位数。
Which is whatever B to the 3d is.
3d中的B是什么。
AUDIENCE: D plus 1?
听众：D加1？
PROFESSOR: OK so roughly either d or d plus 1.
教授：可以，大约d或d加1。
See, d plus 1.
参见d加1。
So a decent approximation would be a 1 followed by these zeros.
因此，一个体面的近似值应该是1，然后是这些零。
An even better approximation is what
更好的近似是
if we can get the first digit right or almost right?
如果我们可以使第一个数字正确或几乎正确？
How would we do that?
我们将如何做？
AUDIENCE: Pick up the first digit of our r
听众：拿起我们数字的第一个数字
PROFESSOR: OK and I promise that r is one digit.
教授：好的，我保证r是一位数字。
Just So let's say we pick up r.
就是说，我们拿起r。
And?
和？
AUDIENCE: We do Newtons method on that.
听众：我们在此上采用牛顿法。
And we just guess one?
我们只是猜一个？
Is that a thing?
那是东西吗？
PROFESSOR: Uhh--
教授：呃-
AUDIENCE: Take the cube root of it.
听众：取其立方根。
AUDIENCE: It should be some kind of inefficient--
听众：应该是效率低下的-
PROFESSOR: Yeah what's some kind of inefficient way
教授：是的，这是一种低效的方式
that we can think of quickly?
我们可以很快想到的？
AUDIENCE: Can you--
听众：你能-
AUDIENCE: Binary?
听众：二进制？
PROFESSOR: Did you say divide and--
教授：您是说分裂，而且-
AUDIENCE: --divide it by 2r?
听众：-除以2r？
PROFESSOR: Oh, sorry.
教授：抱歉。
I thought You were>you were going to say divide
我以为你是>你将要说分裂
and conquer.
并征服。
So I heard binary search, so binary search wins.
所以我听到了二进制搜索，所以二进制搜索胜出。
So we're going to the binary search.
因此，我们将进行二进制搜索。
Binary search from 0 to r.
从0到r的二进制搜索。
Right?
对？
In order to the binary search, suppose I have my guess,
为了进行二分查找，假设我有我的猜测，
g, I want to see how g compares to cube root of r.
g，我想看看g与r的立方根比较。
How do I do this?
我该怎么做呢？
So this is equivalent to g cubed compared to r.
因此，与r相比，这相当于g的立方。
g cubed is to multiplication, so I know how to do that.
g求立方就是乘法，所以我知道该怎么做。
OK?
好？
Make sense for everyone?
对每个人都有意义吗？
Sorry, r.
对不起，河。
My bad.
我的错。
So this is going to be one digit in base, B, so hopefully
所以这将是B的一位数字，所以希望
not too much work.
没有太多的工作。
OK.
好。
But remember this, you can;t do the comparison directly
但是请记住，您不能直接进行比较
because you can't compute this directly.
因为您不能直接计算出来。
So you need to do it this way.
所以您需要这样做。
AUDIENCE: So r is just the first digit of the number?
听众：那么r只是数字的第一位？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So we're going for a slightly easier problem.
因此，我们要解决一个更简单的问题。
We're trying to compute the cube root of a single digit number
我们正在尝试计算一个数字的立方根
to an arbitrary precision.
达到任意精度
You can make it harder, but there's no point right now.
您可以加大难度，但现在没有意义。
So we'll stick to this.
因此，我们将坚持这一点。
So how much time will this take?
那么这需要多少时间？
How many approximations will I need to do?
我需要做多少个近似值？
By the way, so suppose I compute my approximations.
顺便说一句，假设我计算我的近似值。
Right?
对？
So I compute x0, x1, x2, x3, so on and so forth.
所以我计算x0，x1，x2，x3，依此类推。
When do I stop?
我什么时候停止？
AUDIENCE: When both digits are the same?
听众：当两个数字相同时？
PROFESSOR: All the digits are the same.
教授：所有数字都是相同的。
So when one approximation is the same with the next one.
因此，当一个近似值与下一个近似值相同时。
That's what you're?
那就是你
Right.
对。
So these are all integers.
所以这些都是整数。
The moment I get two identical integers,
当我得到两个相同的整数时
I know there's no point to continue because I'm
我知道没有继续的理由，因为我
going to get the same value forever.
将永远获得相同的价值。
Also this means that Newton's method
这也意味着牛顿法
has converged on this integer.
已收敛于该整数。
So hopefully I will get the answer,
所以希望我能得到答案，
which I can convert into the right answer.
我可以将其转换为正确的答案。
OK so how fast does this work?
好的，这工作有多快？
What is n?
什么是n？
When am I going to stop?
我什么时候要停下来？
AUDIENCE: Log base 2 of d?
听众：d的底数为2？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So n is-- so the number of digits in my approximation--
所以n是-所以我的近似数字是-
the number of correct digits-- doubles every time.
正确位数-每次加倍。
So after log these steps, I have the right answer.
因此，在记录完这些步骤之后，我得到了正确的答案。
Now what if instead of doing this I did binary search?
现在，如果不是这样做，而是进行二进制搜索怎么办？
So instead of doing Newton's method I do binary search on 0
所以我没有做牛顿的方法，而是对0进行二进制搜索
to r?
去r？
I can do that, right?
我可以的，对吗？
Because I can get a guess and then
因为我可以猜测然后
I can use this to see if my guess is right or wrong.
我可以用它来查看我的猜测是对还是错。
So in theory I could do it in binary search.
因此，从理论上讲，我可以在二进制搜索中做到这一点。
How fast would that be?
那有多快？
AUDIENCE: And what is the difference
听众：有什么区别
between big r and little r?
在大r和小r之间？
PROFESSOR: Big R is-- oh, I didn't write the big r.
教授：大R是-哦，我没有写大R。
Big r is this guy, here.
大家伙是这个人，在这里。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK, gotcha.
听众：哦，好，知道了。
OK.
好。
PROFESSOR: And this is little r.
教授：这是小r。
Sorry.
抱歉。
Good question, I apologize for that.
好问题，对此我表示歉意。
So R is little r times B to the 3d.
因此，R几乎是B的3倍。
AUDIENCE: D times log 2 of B--
听众：D乘以B的对数2-
AUDIENCE: To the d.
听众：d。
Log r to the d.
将r登录到d。
AUDIENCE: Oh, it's the same thing.
听众：哦，是同一回事。
Right.
对。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
On the y.
在y上。
PROFESSOR: OK so the number of guesses is
教授：好的，所以猜测的数目是
AUDIENCE: Log big r.
听众：大日志。
PROFESSOR: Log big r.
教授：大日志。
And someone was one step ahead and said it's order of B times
有人领先一步，说这是B次
log little r.
日志小河
Or I think it's d plus little r.
或者我认为是d加小r。
So this is order of d.
因此，这是d阶。
Does this make sense for everyone?
这对每个人有意义吗？
AUDIENCE: I didn't quite follow what happened there.
听众：我不太了解那里发生的事情。
PROFESSOR: So I'm doing a binary search on the range
教授：所以我正在对范围进行二进制搜索
from 0 to r.
从0到r。
How many steps?
多少步？
How many guesses?
有多少个猜测？
Log r.
记录r。
Right?
对？
This is binary search.
这是二进制搜索。
R is little r times b to the 3d.
R是3d的r乘以b。
So if we log this, log R is log little r
因此，如果我们记录此日志，则日志R为日志小r
plus 3d log B. B is order one, so we get order of log B.
加上3d日志B。B是订单1，因此我们得到了日志B的订单。
OK so Newton's method is exponentially faster
好的，所以牛顿法成倍地加快了速度
in terms of the number of digits compared to binary search.
与二进制搜索相比的位数。
So if you can pull it off with Newton's method
所以如果你可以用牛顿的方法
and you have big numbers, you probably
你有很多数字，你可能
want to use Newton's method.
想要使用牛顿的方法。
Because binary search will give you a slower algorithm.
因为二进制搜索将为您提供较慢的算法。
OK, how are we doing with these concepts?
好的，我们如何处理这些概念？
I see everyone's unhappy.
我看到每个人都不开心。
Is it because of Newton or something I said?
是因为牛顿还是我说了什么？
AUDIENCE: Can you summarize the difference
听众：您能总结一下区别吗
between binary search and Newton's, again?
在二分搜索和牛顿搜索之间呢？
So you said binary search takes kind
所以你说二进制搜索很不错
of long versus Newton's method.
与牛顿法比较。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So how do you do binary search?
那么如何进行二进制搜索？
AUDIENCE: Divide and conquer, which is--
听众：分而治之，即
PROFESSOR: Divide and conquer, right?
教授：分而治之，对吧？
You start out with an interval, you guess somewhere in half,
您以一定的间隔开始，您猜到一半左右，
and then you see which half of the interval you recurse onto.
然后您会看到递归到间隔的哪一半。
And your interval halves in size every time.
每次间隔的大小减半。
So given the initial size of the interval, the number of guesses
因此，鉴于间隔的初始大小，猜测的数量
you have is log of that interval size.
您拥有的是该间隔大小的日志。
In this case we're guessing a number between 0 and r.
在这种情况下，我们猜测数字介于0和r之间。
So the big goal is to compute cube root of R.
因此，最大的目标是计算R的立方根。
And we're guessing that hey, it has to be somewhere
而且我们猜测嘿，它一定在某处
between 0 and R. So we're going to do binary search on this.
在0到R之间。因此我们将对此进行二进制搜索。
And in order to see how our guess compares,
为了了解我们的猜测如何比较，
we're going to use this trick, here.
我们将在此处使用此技巧。
So the number of guesses we make is log R. Now
因此，我们做出的猜测数量为对数R。现在
R is that number, over there.
R是那个数字。
It's little r times B to the 3d.
它比3d少R倍。
So how many digits does it have?
那么它有几位数呢？
Roughly d digits.
大约d位数字。
So log of R is going to be order d.
因此，R的对数将为d。
OK so if you do binary search to guess a d digit number,
好的，所以如果您执行二进制搜索来猜测广告位数，
the running time will be roughly order d.
运行时间大致为d。
Order of the number of digits.
位数的顺序。
If you use Newton's method and your function
如果您使用牛顿方法和函数
is good and everything converges,
很好，一切都融合在一起，
then you have quadratic convergence.
那么您将获得二次收敛性。
Which guarantees that you'll have log of d guesses.
这样可以保证您有d个猜测的日志。
Log of d approximations.
d近似值的对数。
So Newton's method is a lot faster for big numbers,
因此，对于大数而言，牛顿的方法要快得多，
because you have a log there instead of d.
因为您有一个日志而不是d。
So this is the big difference between them.
因此，这是它们之间的最大区别。
But for Newton, you need a lot of things.
但是对于牛顿来说，您需要做很多事情。
Right?
对？
You need that function, you need an initial guess,
您需要该功能，需要初步猜测，
you need a lot of things to make it work.
您需要做很多事情才能使其正常工作。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: So is that just like the number of times it runs?
听众：那就像它运行的次数一样吗？
Because don't you have a multiplication and a division?
因为您没有乘法和除法吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So this is the number of guesses.
这就是猜测的数量。
The total running time is quite different.
总运行时间完全不同。
You need to jump through a few more hoops to analyze that.
您需要再跳几圈来进行分析。
But this is the number of guesses or approximations
但这是猜测或近似的数量
that each method makes.
每种方法都能做到的。
So if your math would be order one,
因此，如果您的数学将是一阶，
this would be the running time.
这就是运行时间。
If the math isn't order one, then it gets more complicated.
如果数学不是一阶，那么它将变得更加复杂。
AUDIENCE: So what's the running time of a division?
听众：那么一个部门的运行时间是多少？
PROFESSOR: What is running time of the division using
教授：使用该部门的时间是多少
Newton's method?
牛顿法？
It's the same as the running time of the multiplication
与乘法的运行时间相同
that you're using to compute your approximations.
您用来计算近似值的方法。
And it's like two pages of notes to prove that.
就像两页笔记来证明这一点。
So let's not go over that now.
因此，让我们现在不复述。
But the idea is that every time you're multiplying,
但想法是，每当您繁殖时，
you start multiplying small numbers
你开始乘以小数
and the numbers double in size when you're multiplying them.
和数字相乘时，它们的大小加倍。
So only the last multiplication counts.
因此，只有最后的乘法才重要。
All the others are tiny compared to that.
相比之下，所有其他的都很小。
OK.
好。
Anything else about Newton?
关于牛顿还有什么？
Sorry guys, we have Newton on the exam
抱歉，我们有牛顿参加考试
so we have to go through this.
所以我们必须经历这个。
Let's go through some fun graph problems.
让我们研究一些有趣的图形问题。
OK so we kicked off these two.
好，所以我们开始了这两个。
Graphs the BFS edges and graph transformations.
绘制BFS边的图形并绘制变换。
OK I'm going to do a graph transformation first
好的，我将首先进行图形转换
because I think that's more useful than BFS edges,
因为我认为这比BFS边缘更有用，
but hopefully I'm going to get to both.
但希望我能同时做到。
So suppose I have a graph.
因此，假设我有一张图。
Each path is either red or blue.
每个路径是红色或蓝色。
By the way, no political connection whatsoever.
顺便说一句，没有任何政治联系。
And you have weights on each path.
您在每条路径上都有权重。
So we want a path from S to T with the following constraint.
因此，我们需要具有以下约束的从S到T的路径。
So these weights are the costs of, maybe,
因此，这些权重可能是
how much gas you're spending to go on that road.
您在那条路上花了多少汽油。
So in order to switch from a red edge to a blue edge,
因此，为了从红色边缘切换到蓝色边缘，
you also have to pay some money.
您还必须支付一些钱。
You have to pay a cost of 5.
您必须支付5的费用。
So if you're going to go-- if you're
因此，如果您要去-如果您要
going to go from S to A-- let's call
要从S转到A –让我们打电话
this guy A-- if you're going to go this way,
这个家伙-如果你要走这条路，
then your total cost is 3, 1, 4.
那么您的总费用为3、1、4。
If you're going to go from S to B, then if you go this way,
如果您要从S转到B，那么如果您采用这种方式，
your total cost is going to be 3 plus 1
您的总费用将是3加1
plus 5 for switching from a red to a blue edge.
加5用于从红色边缘切换到蓝色边缘。
So the cost for switching from red to blue is 5.
因此，从红色切换为蓝色的成本为5。
The cost for switching from blue to red is 5.
从蓝色切换到红色的成本为5。
And I'll let you guys think of it for a bit
我会让你们想一想
while I erase the board.
当我擦除木板时。
AUDIENCE: What's your goal in playing the best path from--
听众：发挥以下最佳途径的目标是-
PROFESSOR: Best path from S to T. Smallest total cost.
教授：从S到T的最佳途径。总成本最低。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: So any thoughts?
教授：有什么想法吗？
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: It's kind of on the run,
听众：有点儿忙，
but create a supernode connect all the red paths.
但创建一个连接所有红色路径的超节点。
And create another one connecting all the blue paths.
并创建另一个连接所有蓝色路径的路径。
And then try to find the shortest length to T just using
然后尝试使用来找到最短的T长度
those two graphs, I guess.
我猜那两个图。
PROFESSOR: So you're going to create
教授：所以您将创建
a supernode connecting the paths.
连接路径的超节点。
So how does this work?
那么这是如何工作的呢？
AUDIENCE: You create the path from S
听众：您从S创建路径
to T just using the reds.
到T只用红色。
PROFESSOR: OK so I'm going to copy everything and use
教授：好的，我将复制所有内容并使用
the reds.
红人。
So S, C, D, T, and I'm only going to use the reds.
因此，S，C，D，T和我只会使用红色。
All right, red, red, red.
好吧，红色，红色，红色。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: And then-- wait, is that all the right paths?
听众：然后-等一下，这是所有正确的道路吗？
PROFESSOR: I hope so.
教授：我希望如此。
AUDIENCE: All right, and then you're
听众：好的，那么你就
going to try doing that with the blue paths as well.
还要尝试使用蓝色路径。
PROFESSOR: So am I creating another copy of this?
教授：那么我要再创建一个副本吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Let's see, what else, what else?
让我们看看，还有什么，还有什么？
OK
好
AUDIENCE: From S to T, right?
听众：从S到T，对不对？
PROFESSOR: A path from S to T?
教授：从S到T的道路？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, so you just compare the path of S
听众：是的，所以您只需比较S的路径
to the path of T. So you completely
到T的路径。所以你完全
take that out, the additional cost [INAUDIBLE]
取出来，额外费用[听不清]
just by comparing those two and seeing
只是通过比较这两个并看到
which ones are the shortest path.
哪一条是最短的路径。
AUDIENCE: It's correct for this graph,
观众：这张图是正确的，
but it's not correct in general.
但这通常是不正确的。
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[插入语音]
AUDIENCE: And the last option would be combining--
听众：最后一种选择是结合
PROFESSOR: OK so if I do this so far.
教授：好的，如果我到目前为止已经这样做的话。
So I've taken the original graph and I've created two copies.
因此，我拍摄了原始图形，并创建了两个副本。
One that has all of the red paths,
具有所有红色路径的一条
one that has all the blue paths.
一条拥有所有蓝色道路的道路。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: By the way, let's label this.
教授：顺便说一句，给我们贴上标签。
The nodes are--
节点是-
AUDIENCE: So it would work in this specific case
听众：因此在这种情况下可以使用
because you [INAUDIBLE].
因为你[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So if you compute the two shortest paths here,
教授：因此，如果您在此处计算两条最短路径，
you'll get the path using only reds, path using only blues.
您将仅使用红色获得路径，仅使用蓝色获得路径。
But you're not expressing the fact
但是你没有表达事实
that you're allowed to alternate between reds and blues.
允许您在红色和蓝色之间切换。
How do you express that?
你怎么表达呢？
AUDIENCE: Make a lot of corrections.
听众：进行很多更正。
AUDIENCE: Put two layers in--
听众：放两层
PROFESSOR: Two layers.
教授：两层。
OK so these are two layers.
好的，所以这是两层。
This is the red layer, and this is the blue layer.
这是红色层，这是蓝色层。
And how do I connect them?
以及如何连接它们？
AUDIENCE: If there's an edge connecting them
观众：如果有一个边缘连接它们
on the upper graph, we're just connecting them.
在上方的图表中，我们只是将它们连接起来。
AUDIENCE: Or connect the respective nodes
听众：或连接各个节点
and make it a 5.
并使其成为5。
PROFESSOR: Both answers work, they
教授：两个答案都起作用，
have the same number of edges.
边数相同
The last answer is easier to visualize,
最后一个答案更容易形象化，
so I'm going to go with that.
所以我要继续。
So I can go from the red world to the blue world,
所以我可以从红色世界走向蓝色世界，
and back, if I'm willing to pay 5.
如果我愿意支付5。
So this is what--
这就是-
AUDIENCE: And you just use those with the new edges.
听众：您只需要使用那些具有新优势的产品即可。
Or not DFS, but Dijkstra's.
或不是DFS，而是Dijkstra。
PROFESSOR: All right so all the edges here are positive, right?
教授：好的，所以这里的所有边缘都是正面的，对吗？
So I'm going to use Dijkstra.
因此，我将使用Dijkstra。
AUDIENCE: Is there any case in a positive graph
观众：正面图中有没有情况
that Dijkstra's slower than Bellman-Ford?
Dijkstra比Bellman-Ford慢吗？
Because one is like b log b, and the other one is like b e.
因为一个像b log b，另一个像b e。
Right?
对？
So if you have a lot of--
因此，如果您有很多……
PROFESSOR: OK so what is Dijkstra?
教授：好的，Dijkstra是什么？
AUDIENCE: B log b-
听众：B log b-
PROFESSOR: Almost.
教授：差不多了。
AUDIENCE: T log b, I think, right?
观众：我想是对数b，对不对？
That's the theoretical best case ever,
这是理论上最好的情况，
PROFESSOR: So actually, the theoretical is E plus--
教授：实际上，理论上是E加-
AUDIENCE: Yeah, that's what I meant.
听众：是的，这就是我的意思。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
Oh--
哦 -
PROFESSOR: This is what you get with heaps,
教授：这就是堆的收获，
so this is what we got in the P set.
这就是我们在P集中得到的。
AUDIENCE: What was the first one?
听众：第一个是什么？
AUDIENCE: The first one is like Fibonacci heaps.
听众：第一个就像斐波那契堆。
It's got a really high constant factor,
它有一个非常高的恒定因子，
so you never actually use it.
因此您永远不会实际使用它。
PROFESSOR: So this is a nice theoretical thing,
教授：所以这是一个很好的理论上的东西，
and this is what you get in practice.
这就是您所练习的。
If you use the regular binary heaps.
如果使用常规二进制堆。
And so you compare this to Bellman-Ford
所以您可以将其与Bellman-Ford进行比较
which is-- whoops-- V times E. I'm
是-哎呀-V乘以E。我是
going to guess that this is faster no matter what.
猜测无论如何这都更快。
AUDIENCE: Yes, OK.
听众：是的，好的。
So the theoretical one could be slower, then, possible.
因此，理论上可能会更慢。
The Fibonacci one?
斐波那契一个？
Because if you have a ton of vertices without many edges.
因为如果您有很多没有很多边的顶点。
PROFESSOR: OK If you have a ton of vertices
教授：好的，如果您有大量的顶点
but not too many edges.
但没有太多的优势。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Then you're saying that this
教授：那你是说
is going to be bigger than-- so what do you do in that case?
会比-大-那么在这种情况下您会怎么做？
AUDIENCE: I mean you could just ignore the vertices, I guess.
听众：我的意思是你可以忽略顶点。
PROFESSOR: OK so if you have a ton of
教授：好的，如果您有很多
vertices and not that many edges.
顶点而不是那么多的边缘。
So if you have edges smaller-- sorry-- yeah,
所以，如果您的边缘较小，对不起，是的，
it's just smaller than vertices, then
它只是比顶点小，然后
some vertices have to be unconnected.
一些顶点必须不连接。
So what to do?
那么该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: You just ignore them.
听众：您只是忽略它们。
AUDIENCE: You're not going to reach them anyway.
听众：无论如何，您都不会联系他们。
PROFESSOR: How do you ignore them?
教授：您如何忽略它们？
How do you ignore them in--
您如何在以下情况中忽略它们：
AUDIENCE: Oh, I see your point.
听众：哦，我明白你的意思。
So you're never going to get to them anyways.
因此，您无论如何都不会去找他们。
So--
所以 -
AUDIENCE: Well no, but once you've started at one,
听众：嗯，不，但是一旦开始，
you're going to have to touch them all.
您将不得不全部触摸它们。
They're all going to be in the heap.
他们都将在堆中。
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: No, don't put them in the heap
听众：不，不要把它们放在堆里
until you look at them.
直到你看着他们。
AUDIENCE: Well, there's a starting point, right?
听众：嗯，有一个起点，对吧？
If you can't go anywhere in the starting point, you're done.
如果您不能在起点上走到任何地方，那您就完成了。
PROFESSOR: OK so you take the starting point and you do--
教授：好的，所以您以出发点为准，
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[插入语音]
PROFESSOR: Ok so I would take the starting point and do a BFS
教授：好的，我将以此为出发点并进行BFS
and ignore everything else.
并忽略其他一切。
And that is clearly order of how many vertices and edges that
这显然是多少个顶点和边的顺序
are reachable from that.
从那是可以达到的。
So that will give you a nice graph.
这样就可以给您一个漂亮的图形。
Either that, or if you initialization your Dijkstra
要么，或者如果您初始化Dijkstra
carefully enough, this actually only reflects
足够小心，这实际上只反映了
the reachable edges and vertices.
可达的边缘和顶点。
So you never have this.
所以你永远不会有这个。
So either one works.
所以任何一个都可以。
In theory mode, it might be better to say I'll do a BFS
在理论模式下，最好说我将进行BFS
and reduce the graph.
并减少图形。
Because that's easier to argue.
因为这更容易争论。
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: So, for this, when you make all
观众：因此，当您创造所有
that-- I guess my question is are we
那-我想我的问题是我们
going to be asked to talk about running times
将被要求谈论跑步时间
for different transformation?
为了不同的转变？
Or the algorithms?
还是算法？
PROFESSOR: Well so at the very least, last time
教授：好吧，至少是最后一次
we said, this is the problem.
我们说过，这就是问题所在。
Give us an algorithm with this running time.
给我们一个运行时间的算法。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: So you have to be able to know
教授：所以你必须要知道
your transformations.
您的转变。
So not the running for computing the transformation,
所以不是为了计算转换而奔波，
but you have to be able to know how much bigger the graph gets
但您必须能够知道图形会变大多少
and what that implies for the running time.
以及运行时间的含义。
Turns out that usually for these transformations
事实证明，通常对于这些转换
you can compute them in linear time.
您可以在线性时间内计算它们。
So the time for computing a transformation
因此计算转换的时间
is much smaller than the time for running
比运行时间小得多
Dijkstra or Bellman-Ford.
Dijkstra或Bellman-Ford。
So that's why we don't really go into that.
这就是为什么我们不真正讨论这一点。
This one is definitely linear time.
这绝对是线性时间。
So what happens to the graph in this case?
那么在这种情况下图会发生什么？
Number of edges and number of vertices.
边数和顶点数。
AUDIENCE: Number of edges increases by V
听众：边数增加V
and number of vertices.
和顶点数。
So increase by V.
因此增加V。
PROFESSOR: That's V, and times is 2.
教授：那是V，时间是2。
So you plug this into Bellman-Ford or Dijkstra,
所以您将其插入Bellman-Ford或Dijkstra，
you find out the new running time.
您会发现新的运行时间。
So every time you see what is the size of your new graph,
因此，每次您看到新图表的大小时，
and you plug that into the algorithm.
然后将其插入算法。
OK so what is the intuition behind this?
好吧，这背后的直觉是什么？
Did everyone get this problem?
每个人都有这个问题吗？
So it's the old problem that we're going through
这是我们要解决的老问题
again and again, where you have a graph that's 2D,
一次又一次地，你有一个二维图
and we want to compute something that Dijkstra
我们想计算出Dijkstra
can't compute on it's own.
不能自己计算。
Or that Bellman-Ford can't compute on it's own.
或Bellman-Ford不能自己计算。
So in order to be able to compute those things,
因此，为了能够计算这些东西，
we need to add additional states to the graph.
我们需要向图中添加其他状态。
And the way we do that is we make copies of the graph
我们这样做的方法是制作图的副本
that we call layers.
我们称之为图层。
Because we're thinking that if you take that 2D map, and you
因为我们在考虑如果您拍摄2D地图，而您
create copies of it, you basically
创建它的副本，基本上
have a 3D graph where there is the original graph.
有一个3D图形，其中有原始图形。
That's the science part of the problem, the art
那是问题的科学部分，艺术
part of solving the problem is figuring out
解决问题的一部分是弄清楚
what those layers are and how you connect them.
这些层是什么以及如何连接它们。
Because by doing that you can solve a ton of problems,
因为这样做可以解决很多问题，
as we have seen in this class.
正如我们在本课程中所看到的。
AUDIENCE: Is there a possibility that you
听众：您是否有可能
have a very large number of layers needed
需要大量的图层
to be permutations of-- different choice
被不同的选择
to make instead of just a red or a blue?
制作，而不只是红色或蓝色？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So is there a problem where we had a ton of layers?
那么我们有大量的图层存在问题吗？
AUDIENCE: Mhmm.
听众：嗯。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
OK so two problems, right?
好，那么有两个问题吧？
AUDIENCE: One for every second.
听众：每秒一听。
[LAUGHS]
[笑声]
PROFESSOR: And so these are the layers, presumably.
教授：这些大概就是这些层。
We had two problems that had a ton of layers.
我们遇到了两个问题，这些问题有很多层。
One of them was the highway problem
其中之一是高速公路问题
where you had timetables.
您有时间表的地方。
And there, the number of layers was the number
那里的层数就是
of minutes in the day you're considering.
您正在考虑的分钟数。
So roughly, 1440.
大约是1440。
And the other one was StarCraft where the number of layers
另一个是星际争霸，其中层数
was something ginormous, right?
是巨大的东西，对吗？
So as long as that fits the theory, that's fine.
因此，只要符合理论，就可以。
As long as the number of layers fits whatever the problem wants
只要层数适合任何问题
you to compute, its OK.
您进行计算，就可以了。
AUDIENCE: So transforming another layer,
听众：所以要变换另一层，
is that like in V time because copying the number of vertices?
是否像V时间一样，因为复制了顶点数？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, so you should be
教授：是的，所以你应该
able to implement this in order of V plus E, which
能够按照V加E的顺序实现
is what you need to output the new graph description.
您需要输出新的图形描述。
I claim that for this you can.
我声称可以做到这一点。
AUDIENCE: So for E prime, I guess, how'd you get that?
听众：所以我想对于E素数，你是怎么得到的？
PROFESSOR: So for each vertex you
教授：所以对于每个顶点
are going to create a red copy and a blue copy.
将要创建一个红色副本和一个蓝色副本。
2V, this is easy.
2V，这很容易。
Now, the red edges stay in here, the blue edges stay in here.
现在，红色边缘留在这里，蓝色边缘留在这里。
So nothing changed so far.
到目前为止，一切都没有改变。
But each red vertex needs to be connected to the blue vertex
但是每个红色顶点都需要连接到蓝色顶点
by an edge of weight 5.
靠重量5。
So that means that we're going to copy over the original edges
因此，这意味着我们将复制原始边缘
and we're going to add the edges that connect the vertices.
我们将添加连接顶点的边。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So we're not going to ask about the running
教授：所以我们不会再问跑步了
time of the transformations in general.
转换的时间。
Because we assume that they can be done in linear time.
因为我们假设它们可以在线性时间内完成。
But you need to at least have a sense of whether your graph is
但是您至少需要了解您的图表是否
going to double, whether it's going
会翻倍，是否会
to increase exponentially, or what's going to happen to it.
呈指数增长，否则会发生什么。
So let's make a small tweak to this problem.
因此，让我们对这个问题进行一些小的调整。
Suppose that the instead of having this,
假设而不是拥有这个，
I can go from red to blue, but once I've
我可以从红色变成蓝色，但是一旦
gone from red to blue, I can't go back.
从红色变成蓝色，我回不去了。
So I can start out either red or blue, I can go red to blue,
所以我可以从红色或蓝色开始，我可以从红色变为蓝色，
but once I'm in blue I can't go back to red.
但是一旦我穿上蓝色，就无法回到红色。
AUDIENCE: Make those directed edges.
听众：做那些有方向的边缘。
PROFESSOR: From where to where?
教授：从哪里到哪里？
AUDIENCE: Red to blue.
听众：从红色到蓝色。
PROFESSOR: OK so this is how I express constraints,
教授：好的，这就是我表达约束的方式，
in constraints among layers.
层之间的约束。
Before, we had two layers, red and blue.
以前，我们有两层，红色和蓝色。
And we connected them by an edge of weight 5, which
我们通过重量5的边缘将它们连接起来
says you can go from red world to blue world,
说你可以从红色世界走向蓝色世界，
and back, all you have to do is pay 5.
然后，您要做的就是支付5。
If we have directed edges, then this is a constraint.
如果我们有方向的边缘，那么这是一个约束。
If the constraint said there's no cost,
如果约束条件说没有费用，
but you can only go from red to blue,
但是你只能从红色变成蓝色，
you still have to do two layers.
您仍然必须做两层。
And keep track of which layer you're in.
并跟踪您所在的图层。
But then your edge of the weight 0.
但随后您的权重为0。
Since we have to pay, the edge is weight 5.
由于我们必须付款，因此优势在于重量5。
So we can use layers to express additional costs,
因此，我们可以使用图层来表达额外的费用，
or just to express constraints.
或只是为了表达约束。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
AUDIENCE: Does this include back edges, or forward edges,
观众：这包括后边缘还是前边缘，
as well?
也一样
PROFESSOR: Let's get to that.
教授：让我们开始吧。
OK, so does this make sense so far?
好，到目前为止，这有意义吗？
One more question, what shortest path do I want to compute here?
还有一个问题，我想在这里计算什么最短路径？
To make sure that you guys got it.
为了确保你们得到它。
AUDIENCE: Oh, you have to do two of them maybe, four--
听众：哦，你必须做两个，也许四个-
PROFESSOR: OK, I like four of them.
教授：好的，我喜欢其中的四个。
So I have to do SR, TR, SR, TB, SB, TR, SB, TB.
所以我必须要做SR，TR，SR，TB，SB，TR，SB，TB。
Fortunately, our algorithms give us
幸运的是，我们的算法给了我们
the shortest path from one source
来自一个来源的最短路径
to all of the other vertices.
到所有其他顶点。
So I'd only have to run Dijkstra or Bellman-Ford twice.
因此，我只需要运行两次Dijkstra或Bellman-Ford。
What if I want to run the algorithm once?
如果我想运行一次算法怎么办？
What do I do?
我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: You put vertices on the edges.
听众：将顶点放在边缘上。
PROFESSOR: OK so supernode as a source, supernode
教授：好的，所以超级节点作为源，超级节点
as a destination.
作为目的地。
And I connect them to what?
我将它们连接到什么？
AUDIENCE: Zero weight.
听众：零重量。
PROFESSOR: To?
教授：要吗？
AUDIENCE: The two.
听众：两个。
AUDIENCE: Final V.
观众：最终V。
PROFESSOR: OK, very good.
教授：好的，很好。
And?
和？
AUDIENCE: Same.
听众：一样。
PROFESSOR: So what happened here?
教授：那这里发生了什么？
This says you can go anywhere.
这表示您可以去任何地方。
And this says you can come back from anywhere.
这表示您可以从任何地方回来。
AUDIENCE: Bridge between the worlds.
听众：世界之间的桥梁。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
[听众嘲笑]
PROFESSOR: So do we want this to be directed or undirected,
教授：那么我们是否希望这是有方向的还是无方向的，
by the way, does it matter?
顺便问一下，这有关系吗？
AUDIENCE: Directed.
听众：导演。
You can only go one way--
您只能走一条路-
AUDIENCE: Oh, depends on which problem you're talking about.
听众：哦，取决于您在谈论哪个问题。
PROFESSOR: I think if they're undirected,
教授：我想如果他们是无方向的，
it shouldn't matter too much, because there shouldn't
它不应该太重要，因为不应该
be a path where you go back to the source and then you switch.
成为返回源然后切换的路径。
But this would be if you're on a quiz
但这是如果您正在测验
and you don't want to think about
而你不想考虑
that, I'd make them directed just to be on the safe side.
那，我会指导他们只是为了安全起见。
AUDIENCE: What were the four shortest
观众：最短的四个是什么
paths you said we needed to calculate
您说的我们需要计算的路径
for the original problem, before you added the supernodes?
对于原始问题，在添加超级节点之前？
PROFESSOR: So we don't know whether we start out
教授：所以我们不知道我们是否开始
with a red edge--
带有红色边缘
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: --with a blue edge.
教授：-带蓝色边缘。
We don't know whether we end up with a red edge or a blue edge.
我们不知道是以红色边缘还是蓝色边缘结束。
AUDIENCE: Stay in red world, stay in blue world,
听众：留在红色世界，留在蓝色世界，
red to blue and blue to red.
红色到蓝色和蓝色到红色。
PROFESSOR: Yeah OK, cool.
教授：是的，很好。
So let's talk about BFS and DFS very briefly, I guess.
因此，我想让我们简短地谈谈BFS和DFS。
So BFS and DFS.
因此，BFS和DFS。
What does BFS give us?
BFS给我们带来什么？
Why is it useful?
为什么有用？
AUDIENCE: Shortest paths.
听众：最短的路径。
PROFESSOR: Shortest paths in terms
教授：最短路径
of number of edges, right?
的边缘数量，对吗？
No weight on the engines.
发动机没有重量。
So shortest paths using the number of edges.
因此，最短路径使用的是边数。
What does DFS give us?
DFS给我们带来什么？
AUDIENCE: Topological start.
听众：拓扑开始。
PROFESSOR: Hey, man, you had this on the P set,
教授：嘿，伙计，您在P台上有这个，
I wouldn't call it nothing.
我什么也不会说。
OK, how does BFS look at the graph?
好了，BFS如何看图？
How does it partition the graph?
如何划分图形？
Nodes are grouped into--
节点分组为-
AUDIENCE: Levels.
听众：水平。
PROFESSOR: Levels.
教授：水平。
AUDIENCE: The light distance and the source.
听众：光的距离和光源。
PROFESSOR: So you start with a source,
教授：所以您从一个源头开始，
and then all the nodes that are one edge
然后是一个边缘的所有节点
away are at level one, all the nodes that
在第一层，所有的节点
are two edges away are level two, so on and so forth.
是两个边缘，位于第二层，依此类推。
What does DFS give us?
DFS给我们带来什么？
A mess?
一团糟？
A mess, right?
一团糟，对不对？
So it gives us edge types.
因此，它为我们提供了边缘类型。
And it gives us exit times.
这给了我们退出时间。
Exit times are useful for topological sort, right?
退出时间对于拓扑排序很有用，对吧？
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: It also gives us a tree.
听众：它也给我们提供了一棵树。
PROFESSOR: OK, does BFS give us a tree?
教授：好的，BFS可以给我们树吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yes, they both give us trees.
听众：是的，他们俩都给我们树。
PROFESSOR: So both of them will give us trees.
教授：所以他们俩都会给我们树木。
So what are those trees?
那那些树是什么？
For each node, BFS or DFS discovered that node
对于每个节点，BFS或DFS发现了该节点
by going from some parent node across an edge.
通过从某个边缘的父节点进入。
So that edge belongs to the BFS or to the DFS tree.
因此，该边缘属于BFS或DFS树。
How do we compute those trees?
我们如何计算这些树？
AUDIENCE: Just do it?
听众：是吗？
PROFESSOR: So how do you, in BFS and DFS,
教授：那您如何在BFS和DFS中，
what do you compute to--
你算什么-
AUDIENCE: Parent pointers?
听众：父指针？
PROFESSOR: Parent pointers.
教授：父指针。
So that's what you use to keep track of them.
这就是您用来跟踪它们的方法。
Sorry the question is bad but that's
抱歉，这个问题不好，但这是
what I want you to get out of it.
我要你摆脱它。
Parent pointers.
父指针。
So DFS and BFS will both compute trees of the graph.
因此DFS和BFS都将计算图的树。
Are they the same trees or different trees?
它们是同一棵树还是不同的树？
AUDIENCE: Probably different.
听众：可能有所不同。
PROFESSOR: Different trees, right?
教授：不同的树木，对不对？
Let's take this.
让我们来。
S, A, B, right?
S，A，B，对吗？
BFS will give us this, DFS will give us this.
BFS会给我们这个，DFS会给我们这个。
OK, what edge types do we have in DFS?
好的，在DFS中我们有哪些边缘类型？
AUDIENCE: Forward edges.
听众：前缘。
PROFESSOR: OK, forward.
教授：好的，向前。
Cool.
凉。
What are they?
这些是什么？
AUDIENCE: Those are just from parent
听众：这些只是来自父母
to children that are being presented.
给正在介绍的孩子们。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: So, I don't know how else to put it.
听众：所以，我不知道该怎么说。
PROFESSOR: OK so you should have this on your cheat sheet,
教授：好的，所以您应该在备忘单上放上它，
right?
对？
If nobody knows the answer, you should have it
如果没人知道答案，那你应该有答案
on your cheat sheet.
在您的备忘单上。
So tree edges, the ones that show up in the DFS tree.
树边缘就是DFS树中显示的边缘。
Backwards edges,
向后边缘
AUDIENCE: Cross edges.
听众：交叉边缘。
PROFESSOR: Cross edges.
教授：交叉边缘。
AUDIENCE: Forward edges.
听众：前缘。
PROFESSOR: And forward edges.
教授：还有前缘。
If your graph is undirected, what types of edges
如果图形是无向的，则什么类型的边
do you not have?
你没有吗？
AUDIENCE: Forward edges.
听众：前缘。
Forward edges and backward edges.
前边缘和后边缘。
Or no, forward edges.
或否，前缘。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So this is a lecture notes, and we're
这是一个讲义，我们
going to go over them tonight.
今晚要越过他们。
But if you can't make it, they're in lecture notes.
但是，如果您做不到，他们会在讲义中提供帮助。
So you should have this on your cheat sheet
所以你应该在备忘单上有这个
if you don't know them.
如果你不认识他们。
Right?
对？
Nobody answered today, so if you guys don't have them
今天没人回答，所以如果你们没有他们
on your cheat sheet I will be upset.
在您的备忘单上，我会很沮丧。
OK.
好。
Cool.
凉。
More questions?
还有其他问题吗？
AUDIENCE: Edges do not exist in BFS, edge types?
听众：边缘在BFS中不存在，边缘类型？
PROFESSOR: DFS uses-- so out of BFS we get levels,
教授：DFS使用了-因此从BFS中我们可以获得等级，
and out DFS we get those edge types.
在DFS中我们得到那些边缘类型。
AUDIENCE: Is there-- about the edge types?
听众：关于边缘类型吗？
PROFESSOR: Some algorithms use them in their proofs.
教授：一些算法在证明中使用它们。
So the proof for topological sort
所以拓扑排序的证明
uses the fact that in directed acyclic graphs,
使用以下事实：在有向无环图中
you won't have some types of edges.
您将没有某些类型的边缘。
For the other types of edges it argues
对于其他类型的边缘，它认为
that the order that you get from topological sort
您从拓扑排序中获得的顺序
is the right order.
是正确的顺序。
So it's mostly theoretical but since we taught you
这主要是理论上的，但自从我们教了你
about edge types, we might ask you about them.
关于边缘类型，我们可能会问您有关它们的信息。
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: So does DFS actually-- is
听众：DFS实际上也是如此
it able to distinguish between back-crossing over,
它能够区分回交，
or is it only-- does it only see that the node has already
还是仅-仅看到该节点已经
been visited by something?
被某人拜访了吗？
PROFESSOR: So how would you make it distinguish between them?
教授：那么您如何区分它们呢？
You have to, right?
你必须吧？
Because otherwise, why are we studying them?
因为否则，我们为什么要研究它们？
There has to be a way to distinguish between them.
必须有一种区分它们的方法。
AUDIENCE: Because the DFS does recursive calls
听众：因为DFS会进行递归调用
and you know where the back is.
你知道后面在哪里
PROFESSOR: So let's do a DFS tree quickly.
教授：因此，让我们快速创建DFS树。
So suppose we went like this.
因此，假设我们像这样去了。
And then like this, this, and then this.
然后像这样，这个，然后这个。
Sorry, I'm trying really hard to make up an example on the spot
抱歉，我正在尽力当场做一个例子
such that I won't discount myself.
这样我就不会打折。
How do I get that, do you know?
我怎么知道的？
AUDIENCE: Maybe an edge from the second one
听众：也许比第二个优势
to the last one on the right.
到右边的最后一个。
PROFESSOR: Here?
教授：这吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah and this will be the arrowhead,
听众：是的，这将是箭头，
and you can start from the second one.
您可以从第二个开始。
PROFESSOR: This one?
教授：这个吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
Wouldn't that be a forward edge?
那不是前锋吗？
PROFESSOR: OK
教授：好的
AUDIENCE: Because it's downward--
听众：因为它是向下的
PROFESSOR: Yeah, I like that.
教授：是的，我喜欢。
OK, I like that.
好，我喜欢
OK so S, A, B, C, D, E. So assume
好的，所以S，A，B，C，D，E。
this is the order that they listed in adjacency list.
这是它们在邻接表中列出的顺序。
So let's label all of the edges.
因此，让我们标记所有边缘。
SA and SB are what?
SA和SB是什么？
AUDIENCE: Forward edges.
听众：前缘。
PROFESSOR: OK AC?
教授：好吗？
AUDIENCE: Forward.
听众：转发。
PROFESSOR: CD?
教授：CD？
AUDIENCE: Forward.
听众：转发。
PROFESSOR: CE?
教授：CE？
AUDIENCE: Forward.
听众：转发。
PROFESSOR: OK, AE?
教授：好的，AE？
AUDIENCE: Aren't those tree edges?
听众：那些树的边缘不是吗？
AUDIENCE: That's a forward edge.
听众：这是一个前沿。
PROFESSOR: That took a while, guys.
教授：你们花了一段时间。
That took a while.
那花了一段时间。
AUDIENCE: It goes forward.
听众：向前发展。
AUDIENCE: Well no, forward means like you're
听众：好吧，向前意味着你
skipping a generation.
跳过一代。
PROFESSOR: OK so the three edges.
教授：好的，三个方面。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: So the three edges are the ones
教授：所以三个边就是那个
that DFS uses to go forward.
DFS用于前进。
So they're the ones that map the DFS calls.
因此，它们就是映射DFS调用的对象。
So how do we express that?
那么我们该如何表达呢？
So suppose you're at some node u, and you have an edge, uv.
因此，假设您在u的某个节点上，并且有一条边uv。
AUDIENCE: The parent of v is u.
听众：v的父母是u。
PROFESSOR: So you're at here, right now.
教授：所以你现在在这里。
OK, so v.parent has to be u.
好的，所以v.parent必须是u。
And?
和？
v is?
v是？
Is it visited or not?
是否参观过？
AUDIENCE: It's a new vertex.
听众：这是一个新的顶点。
AUDIENCE: It's not.
听众：不是。
PROFESSOR: So v is not visited yet.
教授：所以v还没有被访问。
So this is a tree edge.
所以这是树的边缘。
Now let's compare this to a forward edge.
现在，我们将其与前缘进行比较。
So what happens to a forward edge?
那么前锋会发生什么呢？
AUDIENCE: Parents of children--
观众：孩子的父母-
AUDIENCE: Parent ancestors--
听众：父母的祖先-
PROFESSOR: So you're at here right now.
教授：所以您现在在这里。
And you're looking at the edge uv.
而您正在寻找边缘uv。
Right? so we're looking at the edge uv.
对？所以我们在看紫外线。
uv would point downward in the tree.
紫外线会向下指向树。
What's true about--
到底是什么
AUDIENCE: v.parent is u.
听众：v.parent是你。
AUDIENCE: No--
听众：不-
AUDIENCE: Not necessarily.
听众：不一定。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So v.parent is u.
所以v.parent是你。
So it can be the parent, or the grandparent,
因此可以是父母，也可以是祖父母，
or-- so u has to be somewhere up the tree.
或-因此您必须在树上某处。
Right?
对？
So I can have a ton of dot parents here.
这样我就可以在这里拥有很多父母。
AUDIENCE: There has to be more than one dot parent, right?
听众：必须有不止一个双亲，对吗？
Because otherwise we get tree edge.
因为否则我们会得到树边缘。
It can't just be one parent.
它不能只是一个父母。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: So you'd have to recurse up more than once.
听众：所以您必须递归多次。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So for a node you go up until you find u, and if you found u,
因此，对于一个节点，您一直向上走直到找到u，如果找到u，
then it's a forward edge, otherwise,
那是前锋，否则，
if you find the root of the tree then you give up.
如果您找到树的根，则您放弃。
AUDIENCE: Well then it's a cross edge.
听众：好吧，这是一个交叉优势。
If you go up and you get to the root but-- oh--
如果你走上去就扎根了-哦-
PROFESSOR: Yeah, so if you got to the root,
教授：是的，所以如果您扎根，
it is not the forward edge.
它不是前沿。
Right now we're looking at what does it mean.
目前，我们正在研究它的含义。
So you have to be somewhere around the ancestor chain of u,
所以你必须在你的祖先链的某个地方，
so if you keep following v's parents, you have to see u.
因此，如果您继续关注v的父母，则必须去见u。
If not, it's not the forward edge.
如果不是，那不是前沿。
OK.
好。
And when you see it, did you visit it
当您看到它时，您是否参观了它
or did you not visit it?
还是您没有参观过？
AUDIENCE: Already visited.
听众：已经访问过。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So now we have two more edge types, we have back edges,
所以现在我们有两种边缘类型，有后边缘，
and we have cross edges.
我们有交叉的边缘。
Right?
对？
Show me a back edge here.
在这里给我看看后缘。
AUDIENCE: DA.
听众：DA。
PROFESSOR: DA is a back edge.
教授：DA是后缘。
OK back edges are also reasonably easy.
确定的后边缘也相当容易。
So let's do those.
所以，让我们来做。
What's a back edge.
什么是后边缘。
So I am at u now.
所以我现在在你身边。
I'm looking at the edge uv.
我在看紫外线。
AUDIENCE: It's a cycle.
听众：这是一个循环。
AUDIENCE: Node to ancestor.
听众：祖先的节点。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: It's a node to an ancestor.
听众：这是祖先的节点。
PROFESSOR: OK so who is who's ancestor?
教授：好的，谁是谁的祖先？
AUDIENCE: A is D's ancestor.
听众：A是D的祖先。
AUDIENCE: V is u's ancestor.
听众：V是你的祖先。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So if I keep going, u.parent many times over,
所以，如果我继续前进，你父母很多次，
I should eventually see v. Uhh-- yeah.
我最终应该看到诉Uhh-是的。
So the difference between this and this
所以这个和这个之间的区别
is who is who's parent?
谁是谁的父母？
AUDIENCE: Wait, wouldn't u be a parent of v?
听众：等等，你不是v的父母吗？
Because we didn't go from A to C to D and then at D
因为我们没有从A到C再到D再到D
I realize that I can go to A, but I
我意识到我可以去A，但是我
won't go because it's already visited?
不会因为已经访问过而去吗？
PROFESSOR: Wait.
教授：等等。
AUDIENCE: But assuming that--
听众：但是假设-
AUDIENCE: A is an ancestor of D.
听众：A是D的祖先。
PROFESSOR: So A is an ancestor of D
教授：所以A是D的祖先
because by the time I got to D, I've
因为当我到达D的时候，我已经
already set the parent pointers for C and D.
已经为C和D设置了父指针。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
But-- wait.
可是等等。
u.parent is v. Then u is A here and v is D here--
u.parent是v。那么u在这里是A，v在这里是D--
AUDIENCE: No u is D here.
听众：不，你在这里。
PROFESSOR: I'm at u right now, so I'm at D.
教授：我现在在你，所以我在D。
And I'm looking at the edge uv.
我在看紫外线。
AUDIENCE: Do we have a cross edge in here?
观众：我们这里有交叉边缘吗？
PROFESSOR: Do we have a cross edge in here.
教授：我们这里有交叉口吗？
Good question.
好问题。
What is the cross edge?
什么是交叉边缘？
AUDIENCE: C?
听众：C？
PROFESSOR: OK so this guy is a cross edge.
教授：好的，所以这个家伙很挑剔。
So what is the difference between a cross edge
那么十字边缘有什么区别
and a forward edge?
和前缘？
[CLASS MURMURS]
[班级杂项]
AUDIENCE: It's not an ancestor.
听众：它不是祖先。
AUDIENCE: Ancester goes up to S.
听众：Ancester升至S。
PROFESSOR: So a cross edge is very close to a forward edge
教授：所以交叉边缘非常靠近前边缘
except u is not an ancestor of v. v in the DFS tree.
除了u不是DFS树中v的祖先。
OK?
好？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Yep.
是的
So the only common ancestor between B and C is the source.
因此，B和C之间唯一的共同祖先就是来源。
OK so please get these conditions in the notes.
好的，所以请在注释中获得这些条件。
So as a summary, if it's an edge that DFS uses,
因此，作为总结，如果这是DFS使用的优势，
it's a tree edge.
这是树的边缘。
If it's going against the way of the DFS, it's a back edge.
如果这与DFS的方式背道而驰，那将是一个后沿。
If it fast forwards in DFS, so instead
如果它在DFS中快速转发，则改为
of going one level down, it does multiple levels down,
下降一个级别，它会下降多个级别，
then it's a forward edge.
那是前锋。
And otherwise, it's weird edge so it's a cross edge.
否则，它是奇怪的边缘，所以它是交叉边缘。
One way to look at it.
一种查看方式。
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Is this only true because we
观众：这是真的吗，因为我们
were going alphabetically?
按字母顺序走？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, this depends on the order
教授：是的，这取决于订单
in which the nodes are listed in the adjacency list.
其中节点在邻接表中列出。
AUDIENCE: So it could've been pretty different
听众：事情可能大不一样了
if we went from A to E?
如果我们从A转到E？
PROFESSOR: Oh Yeah, yeah.
教授：是的，是的。
Yep.
是的
AUDIENCE: I'm trying to solve this another way.
听众：我正在尝试另一种解决方法。
The graph information--
图形信息-
PROFESSOR: Yeah
教授：是的
AUDIENCE: --would you say that's moderate or an easy example?
听众：-您是说中度还是简单的例子？
The transformation.
转型。
PROFESSOR: This is on the easy side.
教授：这很简单。
So look at the problems that we had so far.
因此，请看我们到目前为止遇到的问题。
There are more problems in this review packet.
此审核数据包中还有更多问题。
There are like six, seven, eight problems.
大概有六个，七个，八个问题。
It's going to be online.
它将在线上。
It's the notes for this recitation.
这是本次朗读的笔记。
Sorry, bad name.
对不起，名字不好。
So the notes for this recitation.
因此，本次朗读的注意事项。
This is on the easy side.
这是容易的一面。
The StarCraft problem, last time is on the insanely difficult
《星际争霸》问题，上一次异常困难
side, so that's not going to happen.
方面，所以这不会发生。
AUDIENCE: I so don't even get that.
听众：我什至不明白这一点。
PROFESSOR: That's on the hard side.
教授：那是很难的一面。